Michael Fearnley

email: <u>mtfear@hotmail.com</u> phone: 603-507-4273

 $\textbf{LinkedIn}: linkedin.com/in/michael fearnley \mid \textbf{Portfolio}: michael fearnley.com \mid \textbf{Code}: github.com/FearMichael fearnley.com/FearMichael fearnley.com/FearMichael fearnley.com/FearMichael fearnley.com/FearMichael fearnley.com/FearMichael fearnley.com/FearMichael fearnley.com/FearMichael fearnley.com/FearMichael fearnley.com/FearMichael fearnley.c$

Professional Summary

A Full Stack Web Developer with significant experience working with teams to accomplish a common goal. A strong perseverance to solve problems and do everything with excellence. Always keeping up to date with the latest technologies in order to create modern and intuitive web applications.

Applications Built

BENCH STRENGTH

The app that provides Team Leaders the ability to assess employee skills and interests to build smarter, more invested teams.

- NodeJS (with Express) running an API server
- Deployed on AWS for scalability
- Tools and Languages: Angular 7, TypeScript, Git, Bootstrap, Sequelize, Auth0
- Code: https://github.com/benchstrength/stageOne
- Deployed Site: http://ec2-3-80-218-219.compute-1.amazonaws.com:3000

DAILY DASH

Ever been annoyed at needing to go to several different apps/websites to get some basic info? DailyDash consolidates all of that information into a personalized experience for you.

- A full stack application running Express on NodeJs for the backend
- Deployed application to Heroku with a MySQL database
- Tools and Languages: Git, Bootstrap, jQuery, external API's, MySQL, Sequelize, PassportJS, NodeJS, Heroku
- Code: https://github.com/FearMichael/dailydash
- Deployed Site: http://dailydashboardproject2.herokuapp.com/

A NIGHT OUT

An application to provide location based options on where to eat along with a movie recommendation based off of user selected genres.

- Wrote logic for API's and DOM manipulation
- Worked with team to create front-end design
- Tools and Languages: Git, HTML, CSS, iQuery, Materialize, Firebase, Javascript, and external API's
- Code: https://github.com/ashmohney/code-smiths
- Deployed Site: https://anightout-1548896687179.firebaseapp.com/

Technical & Soft Skills

- HTML/CSS
- Javascript / jQuery
- · React / Angular
- MySQL
- NodeJS / Express
- Handlebars

- Firebase
- Heroku
- Materialize / Bootstrap
- Communication
- Empathy
- · Conflict Resolution

- Project Management
- · Time Management
- Energetic & Enthusiastic
- Leadership
- · Team Player
- Problem Solving

Experience

TEACHING ASSISTANT, UNH CODING BOOTCAMP (POWERED BY TRILOGY EDUCATION SERVICES) PORTSMOUTH, NH - 2019 - PRESENT

- Assist students with learning about web development skills including React, Node, MySQL, and MongoDB
- Maintain and update a Gitlab repository for students to utilize

MATERIAL HANDLER, SIG SAUER

PORTSMOUTH, NH - 2018-2019

- Stage jobs with material needed to keep assembly lines achieving desired productivity goals
- Keep inventory accurate and neatly organized

MANAGER, JDK ENTERPRISES

SHELBY TWP, MI - 2018

- Implemented online collaborative scheduling system
- Scheduled jobs for the needs of customers and sent crews to complete contracted work

PASTOR OF STUDENT MINISTRIES, STONEY CREEK COMMUNITY CHURCH WASHINGTON, MI -2016-2018

- Recruit and lead team of 20+ volunteers for all Student Ministry activities
- Improved church communication by increasing the use of technology and online resources

PASTOR OF STUDENT MINISTRIES, HILLSIDE WESLEYAN CHURCH COLE HARBOR, NS, CANADA — 2013-2016

- Build and train teams for the children and student ministries
- Curated content and schedule posts on social media to increase views

Education

UNIVERSITY OF NEW HAMPSHIRE - FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPMENT, 2019

- An intensive 24-week long course dedicated to designing and building web applications. Completed course with GPA of 4.0.

KINGSWOOD UNIVERSITY - BACHELOR OF RELIGION, 2013

- Graduated Summa Cum Laude
- Presidential Leadership Corps